Kheel, Theodore W. Speeches and Articles 6021/005
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Theodore W. Kheel Speeches and Articles
1963-1973
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Kheel, Theodore W.
6021/005
23.5 cubic feet
23.5 linear ft.
Papers.
5767576
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, August 01, 2013
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, August 13, 2015
Biographical / Historical
Theodore Woodrow Kheel was said to be named for both Woodrow Wilson and his political rival Theodore Roosevelt, the result of a compromise between his politically differing parents. The settlement presaged a career in which Kheel would be tapped by mayors, governors, and presidents to settle disputes that were part of the nation's major political and social transitions from post-World War II to well into the 21st century.
Born in 1914 in Brooklyn, Ted Kheel attended public high school in the Bronx. He was awarded a Regents scholarship to Cornell University, where he attended an accelerated undergraduate law school program permitting him to earn a bachelor's and law degree in six years.
In private practice for a brief time after graduation from law school, Kheel soon was offered a position as a National Labor Relations Board attorney in Washington. Kheel's special talents as a mediator and his obvious political skills soon gave him the opportunity to move to a new war-time agency, where he was initially hired as principal mediation officer. By 1944, he had been appointed executive director of the National War Labor Board, with a staff of 2,500 who were hearing 150 disputes a week. Kheel's work at the WLB introduced him to the most important figures in the labor movement and key government officialscontacts he would use effectively in the future.
Following the end of World War II, Kheel returned to New York City and was drafted by Mayor O'Dywer to serve in the city's new Labor Relations Division, which Kheel came to head within a year. With the agreement of the mayor, Kheel was able to serve both in this position and maintain a separate, private law practice.
In 1949, Kheel was appointed to a part-time position as impartial chairman for an important segment of public transit in New York City, a position in which he would render 30,000 decisions through 1982. Also in 1949, Kheel became a partner in the New York law firm Battle, Fowler, Jaffin and Kheel. His skills in conflict resolution led an observer to remark that the firm's work began with a battle, ended by Kheel.
During his more than half a century of involvement in labor matters, Kheel was known above all else for his extraordinary ability to get feuding parties to make concessions to reach an agreement. In the important New York and national labor disputes which he would be called to mediate, Kheel's approach was to protect management rights and at the same time demand fairness to workers while also trying to protect the public interest in the issue.
Kheel's was frequently the voice of reason in settling a number of extremely difficult labor disputes of the 1960s and 1970s. Mayor Robert F. Wagner, Jr., turned to Kheel to help end the 114-day newspaper strike of 1962-63. Among his most infamous cases was the strike involving Mike Quill, head of the Transport Workers Union, who publically battled Mayor John V. Lindsay in 1965-66. Kheel's efforts also included helping coordinate bargainers and mediators during the 35-day New York City teachers' strike in 1968. President Lyndon B. Johnson summoned Kheel to Washington in 1964 to help mediate 10 days of feverish negotiations that prevented a nationwide rail walkout. Kheel would ultimately serve as a mediator and advisor for virtually every New York mayor from O'Dwyer to Beame, for the Kennedy-Johnson Administration, and other presidential administrations as well.
Kheel's interests in public issues were not limited to the labor sector. The policy disputes that came to his attention as a mediator and lawyer frequently cried out for larger solutions, and Kheel was not averse to using his considerable public presence and media contacts to seek redress, especially for what he viewed as past institutional injustices or misguided government actions. Although pressed to do so on a number of occasions, Kheel refused to run for elective office, preferring the role of a labor neutral and public advocate.
Kheel was also not averse to backing his powers of persuasion with legal action: a fierce advocate for public transit, he initiated a class action lawsuit over the Port Authority of New York and New Jersey's refusal to fund mass rail transit. His most sustained crusade for the public good related to his battle to limit commuter auto traffic and control highway building in New York City in favor of increased use of public transportation. Initially attacked by Port Authority officials and some city, state, and federal politicians of both parties, many of the solutions originally proposed by Kheel, including the concept of the subsidized fare, became public policy in later years.
An early supporter of the civil rights movement, Kheel and his wife Ann become involved with the New York Urban League in the 1950s. He served as its president in 1955 and as national president for four years. He worked with President Johnson on race issues and with Martin Luther King, Jr., in a libel suit against the New York Times. Kheel's mediation skills led to important strides in hiring African Americans in the airline industry. His reputation for sensitivity to minority issues resulted in his becoming involved in efforts to add civilians to the New York City Police Review Board in 1965. Kheel was also recruited as a peacemaker in the 1968 Ocean Hill-Brownsville Teachers dispute.
Even though Kheel handled disputes for transit workers, typesetters, and longshoremen, he reveled in the finer things in life, and dabbled as a restaurateur in fine food and was a patron of the fine arts.
He once owned a stake in Le Pavillon, a leading French restaurant in Manhattan, among others. He also represented numerous artists, including Robert Rauschenberg and Christo, and was the prime mover in the realization of the long-heralded Gates Project in Central Park in 2005.
He also made millions of dollars as an entrepreneur while facilitating sustainable economic and social change. He was the lead investor in the giant Punta Cana resort, transforming 30 miles of jungle in the Dominican Republic, and helped bring about the airport that opened that country to tourists and travelers.
Finding the solution to problems such as the impact of automation on the workplace, community disputes, and protecting a sustainable environment in which mankind will flourish, to name but a few, were the focus of Kheel's interest, enthusiasm, and financial support. He was the prime mover, bringing along like-minded citizens and specialists, in the creation of organizations to find solutions to the more intractable issues facing society. The Foundation on Employee Health, Medical Care and Welfare, the Foundation on Automation and Employment (and its British counterpart), Automation House, the Institute for Mediation and Conflict Resolution, and the Earth Pledge Foundation were among the most successful of such efforts. In the same vein, in collaboration with Price, Waterhouse in 1994, Kheel formed Prevention and Early Resolution of Conflicts, Inc. (PERC), now housed at Cornell ILR as Cornell/PERC Institute.
A prolific writer, Kheel is perhaps best known for his encyclopedic work on labor law. Throughout a career that was active almost until his death at age 96 in November 2010, he was able to balance, with amazing success, advocacy of the public good and the management of a successful law and mediation practice and other business and cultural interests.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5024: Theodore W. Kheel Arbitration Awards 5776 AV: Theodore W. Kheel Interviews and Programs 6017: Theodore W. Kheel Newspaper Clipping File 6021 AV: Theodore W. Kheel Audio-Visual Materials 6021 MB: Theodore W. Kheel Memorabilia 6021 P: Theodore W. Kheel Photographs 6021/001: Theodore W. Kheel Correspondence 6021/003: Theodore W. Kheel Arbitration files 6021/004: Theodore W. Kheel Legal Files 6021/006: Theodore W. Kheel Non-Profit Organization Files 6021/007: Theodore W. Kheel Subject Files 6021/008: Theodore W. Kheel Books and Articles 6021/009: Theodore W. Kheel Newspaper Clipping File 6021/010: Theodore W. Kheel Additional Files 6021/011: Theodore W. Kheel Punta Cana Files 6021/012m: Invitation and Program for the Theodore W. Kheel Memorial Service 6059 OH: Thomas Shactman Interviews with Theodore W. Kheel 6194 OH: College of Labor and Employment Lawyers Interview with Theodore W. Kheel 6196 OH: New York City Central Labor Council Interview of Theodore W. Kheel for Central Archives 6207 OH: CLEL Video Oral History Project
Kheel, Theodore Woodrow
5767576
- Aaron, Benjamin. "Should Collective Bargaining be Revamped" (Box 1, Folder 1)
- ABF Research Reporter Summer, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- About the June 1-2 conference on Public Transportation (Box 1, Folder 3)
- The AFL-CIO's New Secretary-Treasurer Lane Kirkland. American Labor, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Scope and Contents
  Jan
- Agreement between the New York Post Corporation and Newspaper Guild of New York (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Agreement between the Board of Education of the City of New York and United Federation of Teachers (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Agreement between the New York Times Company and Newspaper Guild of New York (Box 1, Folder 7)
- American Bar Association Special Committee on Prepaid Legal Services (Box 1, Folder 8)
- American Foundation on Automation and Employment, Inc. A Report to the President of the United States (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Anderson, Arvid - "The Use of Fact Finding in Arbitration", 1969 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Annual Statement of the Cosmopolitan Mutual Insurance Company (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Appendix IV, Legal Defense Fund: Employment Suits Under Title VII of the Civil Rights Act (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Arbitrator on the Move (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Arrupe, Pearo. A Letter on the Interracial Apostolate to the Fathers (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Arthurs, H.W. Collective Bargaining By Public Employees in Canada: Five Models (Box 1, Folder 15)
- The Artists Network: Introduction and Overview (Box 1, Folder 16)
- The Artists Television Network Report to the Board of Directors (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Astor Gerald. New York Dream or Nightmare? Look, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  April 1
- Atlas, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  March
- Aujourd'hui, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Aujourd'hui, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  June
- Automation Measuring HS Social Cost. Monthly Labor Review (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Automation and Public Welfare (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Automation and the Middle Manager (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Automation House: Headquarters (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Automation Proposal, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  Jan 15
- Automation: Threat or Challenge? (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Bacharach, Jewel and James McNamara Office of the Contract Compliance/ Construction and Building (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Bain, Trevor. Academic Governance and Unions: The Case of CUNY (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Bartosic, Florian and Jules Bernstein. Group Legal Services as a Fringe as a Fringe Benefit (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Battery Park City Annual Report, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Beame, Abraham D. report Pursuant to Section 212 of the Charter with Respect to 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Bickel, Alexander M. Notes on the Constitution (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Blanpain, R. Public Employee Unionism in Belgium (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Bleiberg, Robert M. Word and Bond at the Port Authority, Something's Laching In Both (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Block, Joseph L. Government, Labor, and Management: What Should Their Relationship Be?Blum, Albert A. Collective Bargaining: The Key to Civil Rights Progress (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Blumenthal, Eileen. The Solo Performance of Winston Tong (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Books and Bulletins. (ILR Order Form) (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Bordaz, Robert and Francois Mathey. Chefs-d'oeuvre du Musee des Arts Decoratifs (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Britain's Newspapers Meet Technological Revolution. Editor and Publisher, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  May 29
- Britton, Edward. The Scope of Collective Bargaining (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Brooks, George G. Advance Planning For Manpower Adjustment at the Plant Level (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Brown, Sidney Hacking Away at the Old P.A. (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Browne Vinters Co. and Chateau and Estate Wine Co. Taste-Along with the Experts (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Burton, John F. Preliminary Draft of New York City as a Prototype for Local Government CB (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Business Week, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  July 27
- Business Week, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  July 29
- By-Laws of the Authority for Coordinating Transportation, Inc. (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Caiden, Gerald. Comments on the Arbitrage Process - Australia (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Caiden, Gerald E. Public Employment Compulsory Arbitration in Australia (Box 1, Folder 50)
- California Law Review, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 51)
- Carruth, Eleanore Manhattan's Office Building Binge. Fortune, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  Oct
- Cars Versus Mass Transit Competing for the Commenter's custom (Box 1, Folder 53)
- Center for Non-Broadcast Television, Inc. (Box 1, Folder 54)
- Chait, Richard and Andrew T. Ford. Affirmative Action, Tenure, and Unionization (Box 1, Folder 55)
- Challenge Interviews: Theodore W. Kheel. Challenge, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  Jun-Jul
- Challenges of the Changing Economy of New York City, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 57)
- Challenges of the Changing Economy of New York City, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 58)
- Chapter Eight-two of the consolidated Laws New York State Administrative Procedure Act of, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 59)
- Cheng, Charles Altering the collective Bargaining Structure in Public Education (Box 1, Folder 60)
- Chicago Joint Board Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Citizens Budget Commission 40th Annual Report, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- City Almanac, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Dec
- City Almanac, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Feb
- City of New York v. General Motors Corp. (Box 2, Folder 5)
- The City Record, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  July 14
- Claudius-Petit, Eugene, Francois Mathey, Charlotte Perriand, Yvonne Brunhammer and Guillemetter Delaporte. Charlotte Perriand un Art de Vivre (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Collective Bargaining and the Labor Press: A Closer Look (Box 2, Folder 8)
- The Collective Bargaining Forum, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- A Collective Bargaining institute American Labor, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  July
- The Concrete Opposition, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- The Concrete opposition, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- The Concrete Opposition, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  Aug
- The concrete opposition, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  Nov
- The Concrete Opposition, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- The Conference Board Personnel Management Record, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- The Conference Board Personnel Management Record, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- The Conference Board Personnel Management Record, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Conference on Challenges to Collective Bargaining Univ of Hawaii (Box 2, Folder 19)
- conference on Solution to Problems of Automation and Employment (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Connerton, Robert J. Federal Preemption of Employee Benefit Plans (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Connery, Robert H. and Demetrios Caraley. Governing the City: Challenges and Options for New York (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Consumer Legal Services: A Pilot Prepaid Legal Service Plan for DC37, AFSCME (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Contract and Scale of Prices, Newspaper Branch, New York Typographical Union No. 6 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Cooper, Herman E., Thomas J Miley, and Theodore W. Kheel Report to Mayor Robert F. Wagner from the Taxicab P. (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Corey, Walter Vol. I (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Council of AFL-CIO Unions for Scientific, Professional, and Cultural Employees Report (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Council on Legal Education for Professional Responsibility, Inc. (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Crispo, John Dispute Settlement In The Canadian Public Service (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Crossland, Fred E. The Unionization and Governance of Higher Education (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Dazell, R.W. Diversification: Watch the Pitfalls. The Iron Age, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  Aug 16
- The Debate on Tenure Change, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- DaMent, Sandy. There's No Such thing as Model Group Plan (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Dialogue, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  Oct-Nov
- Directory of Services PRB (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Ditchly Foundation A Newsletter from the Provost (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Ditchly Foundation Notes for those Attending Conferences at Ditchly Park (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Donovan, The Rt. Hon. Lord Royal commission on Trade Unions and Employers' Associations (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Douglas, Ann. Industrial Peacemaking (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Draft Matenal for Victor Riesel (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Drougge, B. International Symposium on Public Employment Labour Relations, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  May 3-5
- Duby, Georges, et al. Les Scriptures de Jean Amado (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Dunlop, John T. Structure of Collective Bargaining (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Dun's Review and Modern industry, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 44)
- The Economic Environment and its Impact on Collective Bargaining in Higher Education (Box 2, Folder 45)
- Economists go for the Money and get it. Business Week, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  Jan 29
- Editor and Publisher, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  Oct 18
- Education and Social Change Proc. Of 4th Annual Conference (Box 2, Folder 48)
- Education for Peace (Box 2, Folder 49)
- Equal Opportunity - The Job Aspect Program of the Conference Univ. of Penn. (Box 2, Folder 50)
- Everybody's Money Winter, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 51)
- Excerpt from Agreement Between New York Post Corporation and Newspaper Guild of New York (Box 2, Folder 52)
- Executive Choice: Custom vs. Ready Made Esquire, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 53)
- Experts in Labor-Management Relations The Christian Science Monitor, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  April 16
- Experts in Labor-Management RelationsThe Christian Science Monitor, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  April 20
- Experts in Labor-Management Relations (Box 2, Folder 56)
- Experts in Labor-Management RelationsThe Christian Science Monitor, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  May 23
- Experts in Labor-Management RelationsThe Christian Science Monitor, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  May 4
- Experts in Labor-Management RelationsThe Christian Science Monitor, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  May 8
- The Faces of Collective Bargaining American Labor, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  Jul-Aug
- Federal income Tax Aspects for Employee - Participants in Group Legal Service Plans (Box 2, Folder 61)
- Feins, Judith D. The Mass Transit Fare Structure as a Vehicle for Achieving Better Service (Box 2, Folder 62)
- Feller, David E. A General Theory of the Collective Bargaining Agreement (Box 2, Folder 63)
- Ferguson, Tracy H. et al. Chapter 10: Labor Board Jurisdictional and Unit Determinations (Box 2, Folder 64)
- Fifteenth Annual Institute on Labor Law Southwest Legal (Box 2, Folder 65)
- Fifth Avenue Coach Lines, Inc. and Surface Transit, Inc.American Labor Arbitration Awards (Box 2, Folder 66)
- Financing Mass Transportation: A Positive Approach Final Report (Box 2, Folder 67)
- Finkelman, J. The Scope of Bargaining in Canadian Public Service Labour Relations Legislation (Box 2, Folder 68)
- First International Job Film Fair Film News, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 69)
- Fischer, Ben. Evaluation The Steel Industry Consent Decree (Box 2, Folder 70)
- Fitch, Lyle C. Memo Responding to Personnel: The Civil Service and the Municipal Unions (Box 2, Folder 71)
- Five-hour Day Passes its First Exam Engineering News-Record, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 72)
- For Physical Investors: Western Union Corp. (Box 2, Folder 73)
- Fourth Annual Collective Bargaining Forum (Box 2, Folder 74)
- Fox, Jeanne. Regionalism and Minority Participation (Box 2, Folder 75)
- Furniss, Todd. Steady-State Issues for the Bargaining Agent (Box 2, Folder 76)
- further Wage IncreasesWill They Advance or Retard National Prosperity? (Box 2, Folder 77)
- The Futures Group and National Consumer Center of Legal services Prepaid Legal Services: How to Start (Box 2, Folder 78)
- George, Gerald. How the Mediator Acts as a Key Industrial Cog. National Observer, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- GE's Virgil Day Sizes Up the Pay Board. Business Week, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  April 22
- Gilman, Andrew. Break A Leg. American Way, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Goldberg, Daniel B. A history of the Port Authority of New York Financial Structure (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Goldberg, Joseph P. Labor Management Since World-War II (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Goldstein, Eric A. An Assessment of New York City's Transportation Service (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Goldstein, Eric and Steve Jurow. Improvements in the Federal Transportation Program (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Gonda, Richard, et al. 565 Industrial compensation Decisions (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Goro, Herb. The Block (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Governance of Higher Education: Six Priority Problems (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Gramercy Neighborhood Associates (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Green, Mark J. The high Cost of Lawyers (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Greene, Gael. Restaurants: Exorcising the Ghost at Le Pavilion (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Grimes, John A Legal Services as a New Union Benefit (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Group Legal Services News, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Guide to Fear Employment Practices Order Form (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Guidelines, Informal Controls, and the Market Place (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Handbook of the New England Council (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Hayes, Denis. Can We Bust the Highway Trust? Saturday Review, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  June 5
- Hearings on S. 1423 Before the Subcommittee on Labor of the Senate Committee (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Hechinger Fred M. Loss of Tenure: Return of a Nightmare. Saturday Review, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  May 31
- Helene Zimmerman Productions. Information Unlimited: A Syndicated Cable TV Series (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Helgesen, Sally. The World Trade Center The Village Voice, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  April 19
- Henderson, Hazel. Toward Managing Social Conflict (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Hepple, BA and Paul O'Higgins, Public Employee Trade Unionism in the UK (Box 3, Folder 25)
- History of the Port Authority (Box 3, Folder 26)
- How to Beat Tenure Quotas: The Union Victory at City Univ. NY (Box 3, Folder 27)
- "How to Meditate a Labor Dispute", 1968 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- "How to Prevent Styles by Public Employees", 1964 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Impact Spring, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- In the Spirit of Service (Box 3, Folder 31)
- In the USI News, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Industrial college of the Armed Forces. Developed Maternal Resource Curriculum CourseB-3, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Industrial college of the Armed Forces Developed Material Resources Curriculum Courses B, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Industrial Colleges of the Armed Forces. Resource Management Department National Logistics Management (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Industrial College of the Armed Forces Catalog, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Industrial college of the Armed Forces Catalog, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- The Industrial college of the Armed Forces, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Information on Port Authority Union Motor Truck Terminals: NY City and Northern NJ Truck Situation (Box 3, Folder 39)
- an Institute on the Uses of Law in Combating Racism and Poverty (Box 3, Folder 40)